# Sara M. Krizan

smkrizan@gmail.com Madison, WI (608) 622-0717

linkedin.com/in/smkrizan

smkrizan-portfolio.herokuapp.com

github.com/SMKrizan

Full-stack web developer and project manager with foundation in biology and client services. Extensive experience providing project management for legal, scientific and not-for-profit businesses. Interested in leveraging science education, project management background and skills in JavaScript, Python, MongoDB, SQL and React.js in new role as a developer, product manager, or technical project manager.

### Technical Skills

- Computer languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python
- ➤ Server-side technologies including: Node.js, Express, session storage, and user authentication
- ➤ Browser-based Technologies including: Bootstrap, JSON, IndexedDB, and React.js
- ➤ Database technologies including: MySQL, MongoDB, QuickBase, and FoundationIP
- ➤ Project management tools including: GitHub, TeamGantt, SmartSheet, and Trello
- ▼ Virtual meetings management via Cisco WebEx, GoToMeeting, Microsoft Teams, and Zoom

# Projects

#### Woodland Consulting LLC:

- ▶ Purpose: Website for a lighting design and engineering LLC highlighting work and facilitating communication with potential clients. Includes a concealed and secure admin-login.
- ➤ <u>Contributions</u>: Primary client contact, server connection, models and schemas, service worker, global state, queries, mutations, reducers, actions, and admin page.
- ➤ Tools and Languages used: MERN stack (Mongo, Express, React.js and Node.js), JavaScript, Apollo, GraphQL, Google Maps API, Service Workers, IndexedDB, and CSS.
- ▲ Link to App: https://woodland-consulting.herokuapp.com
- Link to Repository: https://github.com/SMKrizan/WoodlandConsultingLLC

  Link to Repository: https://github.com/SMKrizan/WoodlandConsultingLLC

#### 12 Wishes:

- ▶ Purpose: A website for creating and sharing holiday wish lists with friends and family. Users create a secure login and create a unique link to easily share their lists in a text or email.
- ➤ <u>Contributions</u>: Server connection, SQL database, seed data, controller files, and models and server-side routes, and deployed project to Heroku.
- ▼ Tools and Languages used: JavaScript, Handlebars, SCSS, Bcrypt, Session data
- <u>Link to App</u>: <a href="https://twelve-wishes.herokuapp.com/">https://twelve-wishes.herokuapp.com/</a>
- Link to Repository: https://github.com/chriswein12/wish-list

### TallyMax:

- ➤ <u>Purpose</u>: An application for word-game enthusiasts using definitions, pronunciation-audio, and images to help users identify and retain new vocabulary.
- ➤ <u>Contributions</u>: Concept, front-end design, and the 'getDefData' and 'displayWordData' functions which carry out API queries and de-structure and render API data.
- ▼ <u>Tools and Languages used</u>: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Merriam-Webster Collegiate Dictionary, Pexels and Pixabay APIs.
- ★ Link to App: https://jgrossh2.github.io/word-generator/
- Link to Repository: https://jgrossh2.github.io/Tally-Max/

  Max 

  Link to Repository: https://jgrossh2.github.io/Tally-Max/

# Work Experience

#### Michael Fields Agricultural Institute

Fieldwork and Research Assistant

East Troy, WI

June 2020 – August 2020

➤ Commended for my hard-work.

#### **Executive Director Inc.**

Milwaukee, WI

Program Manager for Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society (MDS)

May 2019 – April 2020

- ▼ Guided African Leadership in order meet all requirements for successful creation of the MDS African Regional Section
- ▼ Lead planning and implementation for multiple international live-education programs and virtual education opportunities.

Project Manager for Society for Immunotherapy of Cancer (SITC)

 $May\ 2017 - May\ 2019$ 

- Provided stability in oversight and management of scientific committees and projects during a period of society growth and increased outputs for the scientific publications department.
- ▼ Managed development and publication of several Cancer Immunotherapy Guidelines, the Society's first textbook and a cancer immunotherapy handbook.

McDonald Schaefer Milwaukee, WI

Project Manager

April 2016 – May, 2017

▼ Worked closely with consultants to organize and manage feasibility studies and capital campaign projects for a number of clients in the Milwaukee and Fox Valley region including those for the University of Wisconsin, the Basilica of St. Josafat, and Riveredge Nature Center.

Rizzo & Diersen, SC Verona, WI

Paralegal

May 2015 – April 2016

▼ Received consistently positive feedback from managing attorney for the quality of my work.

#### Dorsey & Whitney, LLC

Seattle, WA

Patent & Trademark Secretary

*July 2013 – February 2014* 

 Spearheaded process improvements for handling of key documents and for application of FoundationIP software applications.

### Richard Sindell & Associates, Inc., P.S.

Seattle, WA

Paralegal

August 2010 – May 2013

- ▼ Commended by managing attorney for the quality of my legal drafting and research skills.
- ➤ Frequently received client accolades for my skilled and compassionate service.

# Woodruff Scientific Inc.

Seattle, WA

Contract Work as Business and Legal Assistant

September 2010 – September 2014

- ▼ Strategic development of legal systems to secure IP and ensure State and Federal compliance.
- Insightful market exploration for products and services.

#### Education

University of Wisconsin Extended Campus, Online, 2021 Full-stack Web Development; Grade: 94.55% End-to-end application development using Agile methodologies and MERN Stack technologies.

Edmonds Community College - Lynnwood, WA, Advanced Paralegal Certificate; GPA 3.79 Included coursework in legal research, contracts, intellectual property, and med malpractice.

University of Wisconsin – Madison, WI, BS Biology Natural Sciences; GPA 3.38 Included coursework in biochemistry, environmental engineering, and computer science.

Madison Area Technical College – Madison, WI, College Transfer Courses; GPA 3.80 Included coursework in calculus, physics, botany, and macro and microeconomics.